Every piece of data, whether it be text or images,
每一段数据 无论是文本 还是图片
is actually stored in byte-sized chunks.
实际上都存储在字节大小的块中
When an app receives the data, it comes in as an input stream,
在应用接收数据时 数据以输入流 的形式进入
i.e., a stream of these bytes.
即 由字节组成的流
The input stream is an abstraction, that is, it hides the details of whether or
输入流是抽象的 也就是说 输入流会隐藏详细信息
not the bytes represent a file or a webpage or even media content.
例如 这些字节是否表示文件或网页 甚至是媒体内容
It's just a stream of information.
它只是一个信息流
Then when we've received this stream, we need to reassemble the bytes
然后 在接收到输入流之后 需要把字节重组为
into something meaningful that our app can use.
应用可以使用的有意义的 内容
For text data, the bytes need to be converted back into characters, so
对于文本数据 需要将字节 重新转换回字符
the Buffered Reader class allows us to do that.
而这正是 Buffered Reader 类 的作用
We then build up a JSON response string,
然后 我们构建一个 JSON 响应字符串
where the string is essentially a stream of characters.
字符串本质上就是由字符 组成的流
Let's look at how this conversion process is accomplished in code
我们来看看这段代码的 makeHttpRequest 方法
in the makeHttpRequest method.
是如何完成转换过程的
Notice that we start with two variables, urlConnection of type HttpURLConnection,
注意 在开始时有两个变量 HttpURLConnection 类型的 urlConnection
and inputStream of type InputStream.
和 InputStream 类型的 inputStream
Now, instead of returning a final result,
在某些情况下 函数并不返回
like a string, sometimes a function will return an inputStream.
字符串等最终结果 而是 返回一个 inputStream
An inputStream allows you to retrieve information one chunk of data at a time.
利用 inputStream 一次可以取回 一大块数据信息
This is useful if the stream will be returning a ton of data, or
它适用于流的返回数据过多 或流代表的数据源
if the stream represents some data source that will deliver data over time.
需要在一段时间内分批 提交数据的情况
The HttpURLConnection class, which we use to get our JSON data,
而用于获取 JSON 数据的 HttpURLConnection 类
returns the server's response via inputStream.
就是通过 inputStream 来返回 服务器响应的
Next, we have a helper method to read the data that comes from
接下来 我们要在一个方法的帮助下 读取来自
the inputStream.
inputStream 的数据
Let's jump to the readFromStream method.
让我们跳转到 readFromStream 方法
Remember that an inputStream doesn't actually return characters we can read
记得之前说过 inputStream 实际上并不会 返回数字或字母等
like numbers or letters.
可读字符
Instead it returns raw binary data, ones and
而是返回原始的二进制 0 1 数据
zeros, with no specific instructions on what that data represents.
而且并不会具体说明数据 所代表的含义
That data might be an image, a sound or some geoJSON data for us to parse.
数据可能是一张图片、一段音频或一些 需要解析的 geoJSON 数据
In this case, we know that the data coming back from our inputStream
在这里 我们知道 inputStream 返回的数据
is indeed just text, and we can use the inputStreamReader
确实只是文本 我们可以利用 inputStreamReader
to handle that translation process from raw data to human readable characters.
处理从原始数据到人类可读字符 的翻译过程
Now, the InputStreamReader only allows you to read a single character at
但 InputStreamReader 一次只允许 读取一个字符
a time, which can have some very rough performance implications, depending on
这可能导致较为严重的性能问题 具体取决于
how the underlying inputStream is actually providing the data.
底层 inputStream 实际提供数据的方式
For instance, retrieving data from your computer's hard drive
例如 如果一次可以从计算机硬盘中读取 较大的数据块
is quite fast if you're reading large chunks of data at once.
那么检索数据的过程 就可以很快
However, if you try to read data from a hard drive a single character at a time,
但是 如果一次只能从硬盘中 读取一个字符的数据
it'll take a very long time.
就会耗费很长时间
This can be avoided by wrapping an inputStreamReader in a BufferedReader.
为避免这种情况 可以将 inputStreamReader 包装到 BufferedReader 中
Now a BufferedReader will accept your request for a character and
BufferedReader 在接收到对某个 字符的请求后
will instead read and save a larger chunk of data around it.
会读取并保存该字符前后的 一大块数据
When you go to request another character,
当继续请求另一个 字符时
the BufferedReader will then be able to satisfy your request from the data
BufferedReader 就能够利用提前 读取的数据
it read ahead of time instead of having to go back to the inputStreamReader.
来满足请求 而无需再回到 inputStreamReader
So as you can see, in order to begin reading data from our inputStream,
如你所见 为了开始从 inputStream 中 读取数据
we actually pass it in as a parameter to our InputStreamReader instance
我们将 inputStream 作为构造函数的一个参数 传递给 InputStreamReader
via the constructor.
实例
We also supply a character set, or Charset for short, to the constructor.
同时还为构造函数提供了一个字符集  简称 Charset
A Charset specifies how to translate the inputStream's raw data into readable
Charset 指定如何将 inputStream 的 原始数据逐个字节
characters one byte at a time.
翻译为可读字符
That is, it knows how to decode each byte into a specific human readable
也就是说 Charset 知道如何将各个字节 解码为人类可读的
character like a capital A or an equal sign.
特定字符 如大写 A 或等于符号
UTF-8 is the Unicode character encoding used for
UTF-8 是用于 网络上
almost every piece of text you'll find on the web.
能够找到的所有文本 的 Unicode 字符编码
The last thing we do is we wrap the InputStreamReader in a BufferedReader,
最后 将 InputStreamReader 包装到 BufferedReader 中
and we're ready to start reading lines.
就可以开始读取代码了
Okay, I know, these wrappings and layers can seem super confusing and roundabout.
好了 我知道这些包装和层 可能有些难以理解
An inputStream, wrapped in an inputStreamReader,
把 inputStream 包装到 inputStreamReader 中
wrapped in a BufferedReader?
而后者又包装在 BufferedReader 中?
Surely there must be
能否用一种
a simpler way to read data back from an HttpURLConnection.
更简单的方式来读取 HttpURLConnection 返回的数据呢?
And indeed,
的确可以
a read through the whole response's text method would be pretty convenient.
用一种读取方法读取响应中的所有文本 似乎很方便
The problem though, is that the method wouldn't be reusable.
但问题是 这种方法 无法重用
So instead of pre-built end to end solutions,
因此 通常不会预先构建 从头至尾的解决方案
powerful programming frameworks and libraries usually give you individual
而是利用强大的编程框架 和各类库来提供
parts that could be combined together in many different ways.
能够以多种不同方式进行结合的 独立部分
So in this case, for example, the chain of streams in readers is kind of long,
就我们的例子而言 在 Readers 中的 各种流链相对较长
but in the future you'll encounter situations where you'll need to assemble
但此后会遇到需要 以不同配置方式
these pieces in some kind of different configuration.
来组合这些流 的情况
And the flexibility you gain is absolutely worth the verbosity
届时 与所收获的灵活性相比 现在忍受的麻烦
you need to endure right now.
也都是值得的
To test your understanding of why these classes are needed, I'd
为测试你对于这些类的 必要性的理解
like you to describe in your own words, what's the purpose of an InputStream.
请用自己的话描述 InputStream 的用途是什么?
And what's the purpose of a BufferedReader?
以及 BufferedReader 的用途是什么?
Feel free to check out the resources linked below the quiz.
可查看测验下方 链接的资源
Once we know that the HTTP request was successful,
在明确 HTTP 请求 成功后
we can read the result from the inputStream using a BufferedReader, and
我们可以使用 BufferedReader 从 inputStream 中读取结果
then we can convert it into a string and then parse the JSON.
然后将其转换为字符串 并解析 JSON
So what's the purpose of an InputStream?
那么 InputStream 的用途 是什么?
And similarly, what's the purpose of a BufferedReader?
相似地 BufferedReader 的用途是什么?